Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number five in this exercise, we are asked to find the time complexity of this
algorithm.
So this algorithm contain contains a for loop and a system that out that print message.
Please post the video and think about this question.
Solving more exercises by your own is the key of the success and mastering the data structures and algorithms.
So it was through the course we are going to solve many exercises.
I hope you post the video on every exercise and write down your solution on the paper.
Now back to our exercise number five.
The time complexity of this algorithm, we start by the simple one, there is a loop here and a printing
message.
We said that the printing message is oh of one and it is cost.
OK.
It's very simple.
Now look at the loop, we have this section.
The initial condition, they're stopping condition and the increment garnish.
OK, guys, we are going to understand how the look behave in order to get the correct.
A time complexity, so.
This loop starts from equal to one.
OK.
I.
Equal to one.
And I less than and I will consider for demonstration and equal to it.
OK.
And I every time as I times to.
Now, let's start think about this.
Look, we are going to make an iteration table that we have seen before, so I.
Is equal to one at the first stage.
OK.
And.
Is equal to eight.
And what the input here system that out, that print, hey.
I am busy.
Looking at I value, which is one please concentrate with me, guys.
This is the first time this is the first iteration.
OK, now this is executed going up.
I is increased by two, so one times two is equal to two.
So this is two.
OK.
Now I equal to two to less than eight.
Yes.
So go and print again this message and I equals two to.
Now, going up again, I equal that I knew is equal to the old in you, as the old times do.
So your value of Y is equal to two times to two times.
Two is equal to four M is equal to eight for less than eight.
Yes.
So go and execute what inside the loop?
So I is equal to four.
Now.
Going up again, I is equal, I the old I, which is four times two, is equal to eight eight less than
eight.
No, so go and stop.
We need I less than or equal eight to continue.
So this will not be executed anymore.
OK, so.
What this means to us.
As executing three.
Messages instead of eight.
If we don't have AI equal, I times two, if we think about AI plus applause, then we need to have
eight printings, eight printings.
OK, but here and I equal that old AI times too, we are jumping.
I think about it as a.
So we are every time we are jumping to one two three four, five, six, seven and eight, the first
time was one to four.
And.
Eight.
And we cannot reach eight.
So one to four, it is executed, the three times this number is very important.
Three times is very important in math.
We have an equal to eight.
Look, eight is equal to City, so we have executed.
We have entered an equal to eight and we executed the message system that allowed the sprint three times.
This means that complexity is executing three times.
We are executing three times this algorithm.
So.
System, the doubt that print is printing this three times instead of eight.
So Log eight is equal to three.
This means that complexity is equal to is equal to old end and OK, so log eight equal to three, which
means this is that time complexity.